Lourenço Martins O'Connor Shirley Belo

Lisbon +351918593719 | ☑ martinsbelo96@gmail.com | 3 Lisbon

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lourenço-shirley-belo/

@ Professional Summary:

Software Engineer at Fidelidade with a passion for bridging technology and business. I am particularly interested in the intersection of AI, Data Analysis, and business strategy. My experience in Agile teams has sharpened my skills in stakeholder management and collaboration, allowing me to effectively communicate complex ideas and drive results. As a football coach, I've also developed strong leadership and team-building abilities that enhance cross-functional collaboration.

Work Experience:

Engineering Intern, Grupo Luz Saúde (feb 2018 - mar 2018)

- Collaboration in a dose study in x-ray imaging exams
- Data collection and analysis to establish reference levels for the type of exams in question
- Procedure observation and enhancement solution proposal

Application Development Associate, Accenture Portugal (oct 2020 - mar 2021)

Development of investment platform application for a banking client (Java)

Outsystems Developer, Fidelidade (apr 2021 – Current time)

- Development of Web Pages and Backoffices for Multicare's Healthcare Providers
- Stakeholder engagement through business and functional requirements gathering
- Database enhancement and maintenance (SQL)
- Connection build between application and Database through API development (Mulesoft)
- Program Management using agile methodology (SCRUM) in JIRA

Education:

- Post-graduation in Software Engineering, Instituto Superior Técnico (apr 2021–jul 2021)
- Master's degree in biomedical engineering, Nova school of science and technology (sept 2015–mar 2020)
- Managing with AI, Nova School of Business and Economics (dec 2024)

Main Certifications:

- Business Analysis Fundamentals (Microsoft)
- OutSystems Reactive Web Developer
- Outsystems Architecture Specialist
- Design thinking Methodology (Fidelidade)
- Power Platform in Business Analysis (Coursera)
- Data for Business Analysts using Microsoft Excel (Coursera)

Skills:

- Strong problem-solving skills with a solutionoriented approach
- Agile methodologies
- Domain Knowledge in AI/ML
- Stakeholder Management
- Quick learner
- Data Analysis
- Programming languages for Data Analysis (SQL and Python)

Additional Information:

- Languages: Portuguese (Native), English (Advanced B2), Spanish (Intermediate), Dutch (Initiate A1)
- Volunteer Role: Head Football Coach for U14 at "Os Belenenses" Football Club